{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "I thought Pauline _________ like something to read, so I have brought her two books.",
      "a": "might",
      "b": "may",
      "c": "must",
      "d": "can",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "\n\n- Might: used as the past tense of 'may' when reporting that someone talked or thought about the possibility of something",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Paul _________ be in Phuket. I saw him in town only six hours ago.",
      "a": "shouldn't",
      "b": "mustn't",
      "c": "may not",
      "d": "can't",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "\n\n - Can: [in negatives] used to say that you do not believe that something is true",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I didn't see Mr. Ford in the guest room this afternoon. He ___ to the guests.",
      "a": "mustn't have talked",
      "b": "shouldn't have talked",
      "c": "needn't have talked",
      "d": "couldn't have talked",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "\n\n- Need: used in negative sentences when saying that something is not necessary or not always true\n\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "None of them ___ the cockroach.",
      "a": "dares to catch",
      "b": "dares catches",
      "c": "dare catch",
      "d": "dare catching",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "\n\n- Dare: To be brave enough to do something that is risky or that you are afraid to do\n\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Night has fallen. We have to stay here at this inn tonight, ___?",
      "a": "haven't we",
      "b": "don't we",
      "c": "shouldn't we",
      "d": "mustn't we",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "\n\n-Should: used to say that you expect something to happen or be true\n\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What do you think of the camp here? \"Oh, great! We ___ a better place.\"",
      "a": "must have found",
      "b": "won't find",
      "c": "couldn't have found",
      "d": "can't find",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "\n- Will: used to say that you think something is true",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Hey, we _________ eat it, for it is poisonous!",
      "a": "needn't",
      "b": "can't",
      "c": "mustn't",
      "d": "may not",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "\n\n- May:  if something may happen or may be true, there is a possibility that it will happen or be true but this is not certain (= might)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I tried to persuade my father to quit smoking, but he _________ listen to me.",
      "a": "had better not",
      "b": "used to",
      "c": "wouldn't",
      "d": "couldn't",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "\n- Would + have PP: used when talking about something that did not happen, or a situation that cannot exist",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "We can't find Angela anywhere. \"She ___ dancing upstairs.\"",
      "a": "must be practicing",
      "b": "must practice",
      "c": "must have been practiced",
      "d": "must have practiced",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "\n- Must: used to say you think something is very likely to be true or very likely to have happened ",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Someone _________ here, for the door and the windows are open and there is nobody in it now.",
      "a": "can be",
      "b": "may be",
      "c": "must be",
      "d": "must have been",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "\n\n- Can:  used to say that something is possible\n\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "35",
      "subcategorylv2": "9",
      "type": "1"
    }
  ]
}